<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rudraksh Pareek (DelusionalOptimist)</title><link>localhost:1313/</link><description>Recent content on Rudraksh Pareek (DelusionalOptimist)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reddit for you</title><link>localhost:1313/posts/reddit-for-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>localhost:1313/posts/reddit-for-you/</guid><description>Reddit is a great place which if used wisely can work as a great source of information of all sorts. This blog highlights some good subreddits for people who like computers/programming/tech in general. Rather than being a mega subreddit list, this is a curated list that I and some other folks at JODC find interesting.
My two cents There are many other great subreddits that this post may not include, one of the reason being they are very specific to the reader&amp;rsquo;s interest (or maybe I am unaware of them :P) and I leave it upto the reader to find them.</description></item><item><title/><link>localhost:1313/talks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>localhost:1313/talks/</guid><description>I love to talk about everything I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt but feel clueless when selecting a topic. However, I&amp;rsquo;m attending more and more events and trying hard to start giving talks very soon. PS: Feel free to ping, if you have any suggestions or want to invite me over for a talk. 😄</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>localhost:1313/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>localhost:1313/about/</guid><description>Hey! I&amp;rsquo;m Rudraksh Pareek. I also go by the nick DelusionalOptimist.
I&amp;rsquo;m a final year undergrad engineer from India studying Computer Science and actively contributing to the cloud native landscape.
I&amp;rsquo;m very enthusiastic about open source software and have significantly contributed to numerous projects.
I&amp;rsquo;ve served as an open source maintainer for Meshery, a CNCF sandbox project for service mesh management. I&amp;rsquo;ve also worked on the SMI project as an LFX mentee in fall 2021 during which I helped improve the spec&amp;rsquo;s adoption by creating a widely used GitHub action.</description></item></channel></rss>