<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DelusionalOptimist</title><link>https://delusionaloptimist.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on DelusionalOptimist</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://delusionaloptimist.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Userspace Security Mechanisms: Ptrace</title><link>https://delusionaloptimist.github.io/posts/userspace-security-ptrace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://delusionaloptimist.github.io/posts/userspace-security-ptrace/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>There are several mechanisms for protecting applications at runtime. However, what to use and how effective will it be is subject to the application&amp;rsquo;s environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>eBPF is a powerful mechanism which is being used commonly for security usecases these days. It provides deep observability by directly instrumenting the OS kernel. However, a side effect of this is the need of privileged access of some form in the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is also noteworthy that cloud platforms recently have started to abstract away infrastructure, hiding many configuration knobs, so that users can have a more smoother and secure experience. An example is AWS Fargate. Available to use with ECS and EKS clusters, it abstracts away the underlying EC2 instances by adding it&amp;rsquo;s own agent in the usual container data plane and further isolates by running single workload per instance. It also restricts certain primitives as an attempt to keep the enviornment secure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reddit for you</title><link>https://delusionaloptimist.github.io/posts/reddit-for-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://delusionaloptimist.github.io/posts/reddit-for-you/</guid><description>&lt;p>Reddit is a great place which if used wisely can work as a great source of information of all sorts. This blog highlights some good subreddits for people who like computers/programming/tech in general. Rather than being a mega subreddit list, this is a curated list that I and some other folks at &lt;a href="https://jiitodc.netlify.app/">JODC&lt;/a> find interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="my-two-cents">My two cents&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are many other great subreddits that this post may not include, one of the reason being they are very specific to the reader&amp;rsquo;s interest (or maybe I am unaware of them :P) and I leave it upto the reader to find them. Some general advice on finding good communities for your needs and making most out of them:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://delusionaloptimist.github.io/talks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://delusionaloptimist.github.io/talks/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="my-talks">My Talks&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>Talk&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>Event/Type&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>Date&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>Links&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Case Study on Adversarial Emulation Using MITRE Caldera for Kubernetes&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>SOSS Community Days India (KubeCon India)&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>December 2024&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yG2YTgymQQs">Video&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Kueue-ing Up Security for Multi-Tenant Cloud Infra at Scale&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>DevOpsDays Kerala&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>September 2024&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OVBuin3qIU8">Video&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1I2h98ym3EiEMpuKk7XwY5ESsw-I_aRIEbJTpaUM67ts/edit#slide=id.g26b0b30c739_0_35">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Securing Jupyter Notebooks with KubeArmor&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>CNCF Webinar&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>March 2024&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mF8slwTM8bs">Video&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/13DpKV1cv44EU5c3gYKyruy-FGUIuzjemMAL1jPIRsRA/edit#slide=id.g2a7fdceb38f_0_10">Slides&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://delusionaloptimist.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://delusionaloptimist.github.io/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a generalist (or wannabe-generalist) software engineer from India working in the cloud native landscape.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m very enthusiastic about open source software and have significantly contributed to numerous projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my early-early years I served as an open source maintainer for Meshery, a CNCF sandbox project for service mesh management and parallely worked upon the SMI project as an LFX mentee in fall 2021 during which I helped improve the spec&amp;rsquo;s adoption by creating a widely used GitHub action.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>